[
    {
        "answer": "DC Comics",
        "question": "Who publishes Batman's comic books?",
        "sentence": "\nBatman is a superhero who appears in American comic books published by DC Comics ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Batman",
        "question": "What is the name of the superhero that appears in comic books?",
        "sentence": "\nBatman is a superhero who appears in American comic books published by DC Comics ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Gotham City",
        "question": "Where does Bruce Wayne reside?",
        "sentence": "In the DC Universe continuity , Batman is the alias of Bruce Wayne , a wealthy American playboy , philanthropist , and industrialist who resides in Gotham City ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Bruce Wayne",
        "question": "What is Batman's alias?",
        "sentence": "In the DC Universe continuity , Batman is the alias of Bruce Wayne , a wealthy American playboy , philanthropist , and industrialist who resides in Gotham City ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "vengeance",
        "question": "What does Batman swear against criminals?",
        "sentence": "Batman 's origin story features him swearing vengeance against criminals after witnessing the murder of his parents Thomas and Martha ; he trains himself physically and intellectually , crafts a bat - inspired persona , and monitors the Gotham streets at night ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Thomas and Martha",
        "question": "Who were Batman's parents?",
        "sentence": "Batman 's origin story features him swearing vengeance against criminals after witnessing the murder of his parents Thomas and Martha ; he trains himself physically and intellectually , crafts a bat - inspired persona , and monitors the Gotham streets at night ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Batman",
        "question": "What was the name of Kane's superhero?",
        "sentence": "Kane conceived Batman in early 1939 to capitalize on the popularity of DC 's Superman ; although Kane frequently claimed sole creation credit , Finger substantially developed the concept from a generic superhero into something more bat - like ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Batman",
        "question": "What was the name of Kane's superhero?",
        "sentence": "Kane conceived Batman in early 1939 to capitalize on the popularity of DC 's Superman ; although Kane frequently claimed sole creation credit , Finger substantially developed the concept from a generic superhero into something more bat - like ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "1940",
        "question": "When did Batman receive his own spin off publication?",
        "sentence": "The character received his own spin - off publication , Batman , in 1940 ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Batman",
        "question": "What was the name of Batman's spin off publication?",
        "sentence": "The character received his own spin - off publication , Batman , in 1940 ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "ruthless vigilante",
        "question": "What was Batman originally introduced as?",
        "sentence": "Batman was originally introduced as a ruthless vigilante who frequently killed or maimed criminals , but evolved into a character with a stringent moral code and strong sense of justice ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "intellect",
        "question": "What does Batman rely on instead of superpowers?",
        "sentence": "Unlike most superheroes , Batman does not possess any superpowers , instead relying on his intellect , fighting skills , and wealth ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "wealth",
        "question": "Batman relies on his intellect, fighting skills, and what else?",
        "sentence": "Unlike most superheroes , Batman does not possess any superpowers , instead relying on his intellect , fighting skills , and wealth ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "camp aesthetic",
        "question": "What aesthetic did the 1960s Batman television series use?",
        "sentence": "The 1960s Batman television series used a camp aesthetic , which continued to be associated with the character for years after the show ended ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "1986",
        "question": "In what year did Frank Miller create a miniseries?",
        "sentence": "Various creators worked to return the character to his darker roots in the 1970s and 1980s , culminating with the 1986 miniseriesby Frank Miller ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Frank Miller",
        "question": "Who directed the 1986 miniseries?",
        "sentence": "Various creators worked to return the character to his darker roots in the 1970s and 1980s , culminating with the 1986 miniseriesby Frank Miller ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Vertigo and Black Label",
        "question": "What are two of DC's imprints?",
        "sentence": "DC has featured Batman in many comic books , including comics published under its imprints such as Vertigo and Black Label ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Batman",
        "question": "Which DC character has been featured in many comic books?",
        "sentence": "DC has featured Batman in many comic books , including comics published under its imprints such as Vertigo and Black Label ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Detective Comics",
        "question": "What is the longest running Batman comic in the US?",
        "sentence": "The longest - running Batman comic , Detective Comics , is the longest - running comic book in the United States ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Justice League and the Outsiders",
        "question": "What are two organizations that Batman is a member of?",
        "sentence": "Batman is frequently depicted alongside other DC superheroes , such as Superman and Wonder Woman , as a member of organizations such as the Justice League and the Outsiders ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Superman and Wonder Woman",
        "question": "Along with the Justice League and the Outsiders, what other DC superheroes are often depicted alongside Batman?",
        "sentence": "Batman is frequently depicted alongside other DC superheroes , such as Superman and Wonder Woman , as a member of organizations such as the Justice League and the Outsiders ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Justice League and the Outsiders",
        "question": "What are two organizations that Batman is a member of?",
        "sentence": "Batman is frequently depicted alongside other DC superheroes , such as Superman and Wonder Woman , as a member of organizations such as the Justice League and the Outsiders ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Batman",
        "question": "What character did Jean - Paul Valley/ Azrael take on?",
        "sentence": "In addition to Bruce Wayne , other characters have taken on the Batman persona on different occasions , such as Jean - Paul Valley / Azrael in the 1993\u20131994 \" Knightfall \" story arc ; Dick Grayson , the first Robin , from 2009 to 2011 ; and Jace Fox , son of Wayne 's ally Lucius , as of 2021 ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Elseworlds stories",
        "question": "From what comics has Batman been seen in alternate incarnations?",
        "sentence": "DC has also published comics featuring alternate versions of Batman , including the incarnation seen inand its successors , the incarnation from the Flashpoint ( 2011 ) event , and numerous interpretations from Elseworlds stories ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Batman",
        "question": "What alternate version of Batman has been featured in DC comics?",
        "sentence": "DC has also published comics featuring alternate versions of Batman , including the incarnation seen inand its successors , the incarnation from the Flashpoint ( 2011 ) event , and numerous interpretations from Elseworlds stories ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Batman",
        "question": "What is one of the most iconic characters in popular culture?",
        "sentence": "One of the most iconic characters in popular culture , Batman has been listed among the greatest comic book superheroes and fictional characters ever created ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Batman : Arkham series",
        "question": "What video game is based on Batman?",
        "sentence": "He is one of the most commercially successful superheroes , and his likeness has been licensed and featured in various media and merchandise sold around the world ; this includes toy lines such as Lego Batman and video games like the Batman : Arkham series ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Batman",
        "question": "What is one of the most commercially successful superheroes?",
        "sentence": "He is one of the most commercially successful superheroes , and his likeness has been licensed and featured in various media and merchandise sold around the world ; this includes toy lines such as Lego Batman and video games like the Batman : Arkham series ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Batman Returns",
        "question": "What was the name of the 1992 film that featured Michael Keaton as Batman?",
        "sentence": "Batman has been adapted in live - action and animated incarnations , including the 1960s Batman television series played by Adam West and in films by Michael Keaton in Batman ( 1989 ) and Batman Returns ( 1992 ) , Val Kilmer in Batman Forever ( 1995 ) , Christian Bale in The Dark Knight Trilogy ( 2005\u20132012 ) , Ben Affleck in the DC Extended Universe ( 2016\u2013present ) and Robert Pattinson in The Batman ( 2022 ) ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Adam West",
        "question": "Who played Batman in the 1960s television series?",
        "sentence": "Batman has been adapted in live - action and animated incarnations , including the 1960s Batman television series played by Adam West and in films by Michael Keaton in Batman ( 1989 ) and Batman Returns ( 1992 ) , Val Kilmer in Batman Forever ( 1995 ) , Christian Bale in The Dark Knight Trilogy ( 2005\u20132012 ) , Ben Affleck in the DC Extended Universe ( 2016\u2013present ) and Robert Pattinson in The Batman ( 2022 ) ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Batman Returns",
        "question": "What was the name of the 1992 film that featured Michael Keaton as Batman?",
        "sentence": "Batman has been adapted in live - action and animated incarnations , including the 1960s Batman television series played by Adam West and in films by Michael Keaton in Batman ( 1989 ) and Batman Returns ( 1992 ) , Val Kilmer in Batman Forever ( 1995 ) , Christian Bale in The Dark Knight Trilogy ( 2005\u20132012 ) , Ben Affleck in the DC Extended Universe ( 2016\u2013present ) and Robert Pattinson in The Batman ( 2022 ) ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Batman Returns",
        "question": "What was the name of the 1992 film that featured Michael Keaton as Batman?",
        "sentence": "Batman has been adapted in live - action and animated incarnations , including the 1960s Batman television series played by Adam West and in films by Michael Keaton in Batman ( 1989 ) and Batman Returns ( 1992 ) , Val Kilmer in Batman Forever ( 1995 ) , Christian Bale in The Dark Knight Trilogy ( 2005\u20132012 ) , Ben Affleck in the DC Extended Universe ( 2016\u2013present ) and Robert Pattinson in The Batman ( 2022 ) ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Batman Returns",
        "question": "What was the name of the 1992 film that featured Michael Keaton as Batman?",
        "sentence": "Batman has been adapted in live - action and animated incarnations , including the 1960s Batman television series played by Adam West and in films by Michael Keaton in Batman ( 1989 ) and Batman Returns ( 1992 ) , Val Kilmer in Batman Forever ( 1995 ) , Christian Bale in The Dark Knight Trilogy ( 2005\u20132012 ) , Ben Affleck in the DC Extended Universe ( 2016\u2013present ) and Robert Pattinson in The Batman ( 2022 ) ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Batman",
        "question": "What television series has been adapted in live action and animated incarnations?",
        "sentence": "Batman has been adapted in live - action and animated incarnations , including the 1960s Batman television series played by Adam West and in films by Michael Keaton in Batman ( 1989 ) and Batman Returns ( 1992 ) , Val Kilmer in Batman Forever ( 1995 ) , Christian Bale in The Dark Knight Trilogy ( 2005\u20132012 ) , Ben Affleck in the DC Extended Universe ( 2016\u2013present ) and Robert Pattinson in The Batman ( 2022 ) ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Batman Returns",
        "question": "What was the name of the 1992 film that featured Michael Keaton as Batman?",
        "sentence": "Batman has been adapted in live - action and animated incarnations , including the 1960s Batman television series played by Adam West and in films by Michael Keaton in Batman ( 1989 ) and Batman Returns ( 1992 ) , Val Kilmer in Batman Forever ( 1995 ) , Christian Bale in The Dark Knight Trilogy ( 2005\u20132012 ) , Ben Affleck in the DC Extended Universe ( 2016\u2013present ) and Robert Pattinson in The Batman ( 2022 ) ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Batman",
        "question": "What television series has been adapted in live action and animated incarnations?",
        "sentence": "Batman has been adapted in live - action and animated incarnations , including the 1960s Batman television series played by Adam West and in films by Michael Keaton in Batman ( 1989 ) and Batman Returns ( 1992 ) , Val Kilmer in Batman Forever ( 1995 ) , Christian Bale in The Dark Knight Trilogy ( 2005\u20132012 ) , Ben Affleck in the DC Extended Universe ( 2016\u2013present ) and Robert Pattinson in The Batman ( 2022 ) ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Kevin Conroy",
        "question": "Who provided the voice for the character?",
        "sentence": "Kevin Conroy , Jason O'Mara , and Will Arnett , among others , have provided the character 's voice ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Will Arnett",
        "question": "Along with Kevin Conroy, Jason O'Mara, and Jason O'Mara, who provided the character's voice?",
        "sentence": "Kevin Conroy , Jason O'Mara , and Will Arnett , among others , have provided the character 's voice ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Bob Kane",
        "question": "Who created the Bat - Man?",
        "sentence": "In response , Bob Kane created \" the Bat - Man \" ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "two",
        "question": "How many stiff wings did he have?",
        "sentence": "He had two stiff wings that were sticking out , looking like bat wings ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "removing the red sections",
        "question": "What did Finger recommend from the original costume?",
        "sentence": "Finger suggested giving the character a cowl instead of a simple domino mask , a cape instead of wings , and gloves ; he also recommended removing the red sections from the original costume ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Robert the Bruce",
        "question": "What was Bruce Wayne's first name?",
        "sentence": "Finger said he devised the namefor the character 's secret identity : \" Bruce Wayne 's first name came from Robert the Bruce , the Scottish patriot ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "the Scottish patriot",
        "question": "What was Bruce Wayne's first name?",
        "sentence": "Finger said he devised the namefor the character 's secret identity : \" Bruce Wayne 's first name came from Robert the Bruce , the Scottish patriot ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Kane and Finger",
        "question": "Who drew inspiration from 1930s popular culture?",
        "sentence": "Kane and Finger drew upon contemporary 1930s popular culture for inspiration regarding much of the Bat - Man 's look , personality , methods , and weaponry ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "1930s",
        "question": "In what decade did Kane and Finger draw inspiration from popular culture?",
        "sentence": "Kane and Finger drew upon contemporary 1930s popular culture for inspiration regarding much of the Bat - Man 's look , personality , methods , and weaponry ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Baroness Emmuska Orczy",
        "question": "Who created the Scarlet Pimpernel?",
        "sentence": "As an aristocratic hero with a double identity , Batman had predecessors in the Scarlet Pimpernel ( created by Baroness Emmuska Orczy , 1903 ) and Zorro ( created by Johnston McCulley , 1919 ) ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Johnston McCulley",
        "question": "Who created Zorro?",
        "sentence": "As an aristocratic hero with a double identity , Batman had predecessors in the Scarlet Pimpernel ( created by Baroness Emmuska Orczy , 1903 ) and Zorro ( created by Johnston McCulley , 1919 ) ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "aloof",
        "question": "Batman averted suspicion by playing what in public?",
        "sentence": "Like them , Batman performed his heroic deeds in secret , averted suspicion by playing aloof in public , and marked his work with a signature symbol ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "aloof",
        "question": "Batman averted suspicion by playing what in public?",
        "sentence": "Like them , Batman performed his heroic deeds in secret , averted suspicion by playing aloof in public , and marked his work with a signature symbol ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "1920",
        "question": "In what year was The Mark of Zorro released?",
        "sentence": "Kane noted the influence of the films The Mark of Zorro ( 1920 ) and The Bat Whispers ( 1930 ) in the creation of the character 's iconography ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "The Bat Whispers",
        "question": "What film influenced Kane's character's iconography?",
        "sentence": "Kane noted the influence of the films The Mark of Zorro ( 1920 ) and The Bat Whispers ( 1930 ) in the creation of the character 's iconography ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Doc Savage",
        "question": "Along with The Shadow, Dick Tracy, and Sherlock Holmes, what pulp hero inspired Finger?",
        "sentence": "Finger , drawing inspiration from pulp heroes like Doc Savage , The Shadow , Dick Tracy , and Sherlock Holmes , made the character a master sleuth ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "1989",
        "question": "When did Kane write his autobiography?",
        "sentence": "In his 1989 autobiography , Kane detailed Finger 's contributions to Batman 's creation : One day I called Bill and said , ' I have a new character called the Bat - Man and I 've made some crude , elementary sketches I 'd like you to look at . '"
    },
    {
        "answer": "hood",
        "question": "What did Bill put on him to make him look more like a bat?",
        "sentence": "Bill said , ' Why not make him look more like a bat and put a hood on him , and take the eyeballs out and just put slits for eyes to make him look more mysterious ? '"
    },
    {
        "answer": "hood",
        "question": "What did Bill put on him to make him look more like a bat?",
        "sentence": "Bill said , ' Why not make him look more like a bat and put a hood on him , and take the eyeballs out and just put slits for eyes to make him look more mysterious ? '"
    },
    {
        "answer": "hood",
        "question": "What did Bill put on him to make him look more like a bat?",
        "sentence": "Bill said , ' Why not make him look more like a bat and put a hood on him , and take the eyeballs out and just put slits for eyes to make him look more mysterious ? '"
    },
    {
        "answer": "hood",
        "question": "What did Bill put on him to make him look more like a bat?",
        "sentence": "Bill said , ' Why not make him look more like a bat and put a hood on him , and take the eyeballs out and just put slits for eyes to make him look more mysterious ? '"
    },
    {
        "answer": "the Bat - Man",
        "question": "Who wore a red union suit?",
        "sentence": "At this point , the Bat - Man wore a red union suit ; the wings , trunks , and mask were black ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "two",
        "question": "How many bat wings did the cape have?",
        "sentence": "The cape looked like two stiff bat wings attached to his arms ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "bat wings",
        "question": "What did Bat-Man's wings look like when he was fighting or swinging down on a rope?",
        "sentence": "As Bill and I talked , we realized that these wings would get cumbersome when Bat - Man was in action and changed them into a cape , scalloped to look like bat wings when he was fighting or swinging down on a rope ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "bat wings",
        "question": "What did Bat-Man's wings look like when he was fighting or swinging down on a rope?",
        "sentence": "As Bill and I talked , we realized that these wings would get cumbersome when Bat - Man was in action and changed them into a cape , scalloped to look like bat wings when he was fighting or swinging down on a rope ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "gloves",
        "question": "What did he not have on him?",
        "sentence": "Also , he did n't have any gloves on , and we added them so that he would n't leave fingerprints ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "fingerprints",
        "question": "We added gloves so that he wouldn't leave what?",
        "sentence": "Also , he did n't have any gloves on , and we added them so that he would n't leave fingerprints ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "byline",
        "question": "What is mandatory on all Batman comics?",
        "sentence": "Kane signed away ownership in the character in exchange for , among other compensation , a mandatory byline on all Batman comics ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Bob Kane",
        "question": "Who created Batman?",
        "sentence": "This byline did not originally say \" Batman created by Bob Kane \" ; his name was simply written on the title page of each story ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "comic book",
        "question": "Where did the name of the author of a story disappear in the mid-1960s?",
        "sentence": "The name disappeared from the comic book in the mid-1960s , replaced by credits for each story 's actual writer and artists ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "credits",
        "question": "What was the name of each comic book's writer and artists replaced by?",
        "sentence": "The name disappeared from the comic book in the mid-1960s , replaced by credits for each story 's actual writer and artists ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Jerry Siegel and Joe Shuster",
        "question": "Who received a \"created by\" credit on Superman titles in the late 1970s?",
        "sentence": "In the late 1970s , when Jerry Siegel and Joe Shuster began receiving a \" created by \" credit on the Superman titles , along with William Moulton Marston being given the byline for creating Wonder Woman , Batman stories began saying \" Created by Bob Kane \" in addition to the other credits ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Bob Kane",
        "question": "Who created Wonder Woman?",
        "sentence": "In the late 1970s , when Jerry Siegel and Joe Shuster began receiving a \" created by \" credit on the Superman titles , along with William Moulton Marston being given the byline for creating Wonder Woman , Batman stories began saying \" Created by Bob Kane \" in addition to the other credits ."
    }
]